# **Dinika Saxena**

A former software engineering intern at CERN, I specialize in front-end engineering. I am highly focused on developing high performance web applications from the ground up using sound engineering principles, as can be proven from my work experiences and projects.

e-mail website aithub bloa linkedIn codepen phone

dinika.saxenas@gmail.com dinika.github.io/portfolio/ github.com/Dinika dinikasaxena.wordpress.com linkedin.com/in/dinika-saxena codepen.io/Dinika +91 8375 042 615

## **Work Experience**

#### Front-End Engineer @ CERN, Switzerland

(Sept 2017 - Oct 2018)

Technologies used - React, Redux, Angular, TypeScript, ImmutableJS, Jest, Enzyme, Puppeteer, Jasmine, Python, SCSS, Git, Docker, Agile methodology

- Migrated the front-end architecture of Inspire, an open access repository for the High Energy Physics community, from Angular to React
- Reduced complexity of the system by designing RESTful APIs that send normalized data which requires minimum additional processing on the front-end side
- Designed mock-ups and conducted user tests to make sure that the development road-map of the new application is properly aligned with the user requirements Link to case-study - https://dinika.github.io/portfolio/inspire.html

#### Android App Developer @ DU Innovation Desk, India

(Nov 2015 - Nov 2016)

Technologies Used - Java and Python

- Led an inter-disciplinary team to develop an android application, Health Buddy, aimed at tracking and improving nutrient intake of users
- Conducted statistical analysis (using Python) to check & increase its efficiency

### Software Engineer Intern @ CERN, Switzerland

(June - Aug 2016)

Technologies Used - D3.JS, Dimple, SVG, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, BootStrap

- Designed a visualization for the OpenStack cloud infrastructure at CERN using D3.JS
- ► Developed a dashboard for the cloud engineers that uses the visualization to reduce the cognitive load required to quickly detect and fix faulty VMs
- Awarded 2nd prize for best project presentation at CERN Lightning talks 2016 Link to case-study - https://dinika.github.io/portfolio/cern-dashboard.html



#### UI/UX Developer @ Binary Dots, India

(June 2014 - July 2015)

Technologies Used - Adobe Creative Suite, BootStrap, HTML, CSS

- Designed in-house and client (responsive) websites, billboard ads, and brochures
- Awarded employee of the month thrice for my work in solidifying brand direction



# Relevant Projects &

- ▶ Improved performance of a website by 216% on desktops and 232% on mobile devices by optimizing the Critical Rendering Path Link to case-study
- ▶ Demonstrated security and performance benefits of HTTP2 over HTTP/1.1 by simulating attacks on vulnerabilities of several websites (such as eBay, NASA)
- ▶ Developed a full-stack web application using React, Redux, Webpack and Firebase that allows authorized users to build and buy customized burgers
- ► Contributed to Mozilla's new web browser, Servo by submitting JS demos for performance auditing and reporting build issues on Linux and Windows
- ► Participated in **JS Hackathon 2018** at CERN and built an application using Angular that calls CERN's API and allows users to search and play videos GitHub Repository
- ▶ Developed an application that uses AJAX to call the Google Street View, NY Times, and the MediaWiki APIs to display information on a chosen city GitHub Repository
- ► Creating a series of web experiments on domains ranging from web animations to data visualization on Codepen; Codepen Profile
- ▶ Built a private cloud for the college using RDO (OpenStack) on CentOS 6

### Skills

JavaScript (ES6)

CSS

HTML

SASS/SCSS

BootStrap

React

Redux

Enzyme

Jest

Jasmine

Puppeteer

**TypeScript** 

Firebase

**ImmutableJS** 

Webpack

Python

Git

PageSpeed

Typography

# **Education**

B.Tech in CS

University of Delhi (2013-17) 93.3%

Awarded excellence prize for obtaining 3<sup>rd</sup> highest scores in college

### **Achievements**

- ► Grace Hopper Scholarship awarded by the Anita Borg Institute (Dec 2015)
- ► CSSS Scholarship awarded by the Central Indian Govt. for exemplary performance to cover graduation from 2013 to 2017
- ► Successfully completed the Hacktoberfest 2016, 2017
- ▶ 1st prize in Best Paper Presentation for paper on 'Quantum Key Distribution' presented at NCAECA 2016